（デイダラ）フッ
（我愛羅があら）ん？
（デイダラ）う…
（砂すなの里さとの忍しのび）うわあ…
Wh-What's that?
（砂の里の忍）あ… なんだ？
Just a little more.
（デイダラ）もう少しだ
あっ
You're pretty good.
なかなかやるなあ うん
Now that's a handy Jinchuriki.
（デイダラ）ほう 便利な人柱力(じんちゅうりき)だな
But... how'd you know
I was the intruder?
（デイダラ）しかし
オイラが よく分かったな
There are no birds like that
in this desert.
この砂漠に そんな鳥はいない
I see.
なるほど
♪～
A voice heard in the distance gives me a hint.
tooku de kikoeru koe wo hinto ni
One by one like-minded people are standing up.
hitori mata hitori tachiagaru doushi
Lets overturn all the everyday, monotonous things.
kurikaesu dake no fudan doori kutsugaesu
I'm ready, are you ready?
junbi iize are you ready
A shiver spreads through my body, violently ringing stomping.
karadajuu furuwasu shindou ni hageshiku uchinarase yo stomping
Constantly stirring in me, it calls me.
taezu tsuki ugokasu call me
Catching that unchanging, never wavering story, Come on!
kawarazu yuru ga nutsukamu story come on
Everybody stand up! Today's the best time to get up!
everybody stand up agero kyou ichiban no jikan da
Before my eyes you still don't stop, speed hunter.
me ni mo tomaranu speed hunter
Everyone is a victim to that attraction, Yeah! (Come on!)
daremo ga mina toriko kanban yeah come on
Everybody Hands up! It's the highly anticipated Hero's Come Back!
everybody hands up matashita na hero's come back
Hold up your fingers and count down.
zujou kazoe yubi oru count down
Let's go, 3-2-1 make some noise!
ikuze 3-2-1 make some noise
Are you ready for a few risks?
hey yo whoa tashou no risuku wa kakugo desho
You have to get up no matter how many times you fall. (Get it on!)
nanka korundatte tatsu get it on
It's not some conspiracy, just a paper-thin session
nare ai ja nai ze kami hitoe no sesshon
The pent up feelings turn into a crystal.
irikunda kanjou kidzukiageta kesshou
The rising cheers will become your courage.
wakiagaru kansei ga yuuki tonaru
So stand up now, no matter how much pain you feel.
tachiagareba ima ijou kurushimi tomonau
But in the end I'm sure you'll laugh.
soredemo saigo wa kitto warau
Everything will be swept away in victory and cheer.
subete sarau shouri to kansei
Everybody stand up! Today's the best time to get up!
everybody stand up agero kyou ichiban no jikan da
Before my eyes you still don't stop, speed hunter.
me ni mo tomaranu speed hunter
Everyone is a victim to that attraction, Yeah! (Come on!)
daremo ga mina toriko kanban yeah come on
Everybody Hands up! It's the highly anticipated Hero's Come Back!
everybody hands up matashita na hero's come back
～♪
Hold up your fingers and count down.
zujou kazoe yubi oru count down
Let's go, 3-2-1 make some noise!
ikuze 3-2-1 make some noise
The Jinchuriki
of the Sand
You're pretty good...
なかなかやるなあ うん
（デイダラ）ほう 便利な人柱力だな
Now that's a handy Jinchuriki.
（デイダラ）しかし
オイラが よく分かったな
But... how'd you know
I was the intruder?
この砂漠に そんな鳥はいない
There are no birds like that
in this desert.
I see.
なるほど
（砂の里の忍）おい
さっきの物音はなんだ
Hey! What was that noise earlier?!
You're supposed to report immediately
if something happens...
何かあったら すぐ報告を…
あ…
こ これは…
Wh-What... happened?
ああっ
Kazekage-sama...
風影かぜかげ様
What do you mean something strange
got into the village?!
（カンクロウ）変なのが
里に入り込んでいるって
どういうことだ
里の守りは 由良ゆうら隊長が
がっちり固めてるはずじゃん
Captain Yuura was supposed to have
tightened village security.
（砂の里の忍）それが…
Actually... we have been unable to
contact Captain Yuura.
その由良隊長と
連絡がつかない状態なのです
Come again?!
なんだと？
（サソリ）あ～あ
結局 大騒ぎにしちまって
Oh, man... That Deidara had to go
and turn this into a circus.
デイダラのやつ
由良
Yuura.
You head on back.
お前 先に行ってろ
里の連中に見つかると
いろいろと面倒だからな
Things will get complicated if the guys
from the village find you here.
（由良）はっ サソリ様
Yes, Sasori-sama.
Get a move on, Deidara.
（サソリ）早くしろよ デイダラ
I don't like to be kept waiting.
俺は 待たされるのが
好きじゃねえからな
（カンクロウ）我愛羅 入るぞ
Gaara! I'm coming in!
どこに行ったんだ
Where'd he go...?
（砂の里の忍）カンクロウ
Kankuro, the Kazekage-sama is
fighting up in the sky.
風影様が 上で戦ってらっしゃるぞ
Wh-What did you say?
なっ なんだと！
我愛羅
Gaara...!
ハッ
隠密行動は失敗だな うん
The covert action is a failure.
ハハッ
だが おかげで
てめえを捜す手間が省けたぜ
But now...
I don't have to bother...
looking for you anymore...!
（我愛羅）んんっ！
ああ…
さすが地の利があるか
He's got the advantage,
as expected...
やっかいだな うん
This is a real mess.
Over there?!
（ナルト）そこか！
（カカシ）あっ
（カカシ）こいつは…
This one is?!
ナルトの影分身かげぶんしんの変化へんげか
A transformation of one
of Naruto's Shadow Clones, huh?!
（カカシ）なっ
（カカシ）かすっただけでアウトだな
I'm finished if it even grazes me...
（サクラ）チッ
（カカシ）忍戦術の心得 その３
Shinobi Battle Skills, part three...
忍術にんじゅつ
Ninjutsu!
The speed of his seal forming...
（サクラ）印を結ぶスピードが…
（ナルト）速すぎるってばよ
It's way too fast!
（カカシ）はあ～
火遁かとん 豪火球ごうかきゅうの術
Fire Style! Fireball Jutsu!
（ナルト）うっ…
（サクラ）うわっ
カカシ先生は…
Where's Kakashi-sensei?
あっ…
Earth Style: Headhunter Jutsu!
土遁どどん 心中斬首しんちゅうざんしゅの術
えっ？
うっ うわっ
（カカシ）影分身か
A Shadow Clone, huh?!
水遁すいとん 水龍弾すいりゅうだんの術
Water Style! Water Dragon Missile!
（ナルト）うわっ 何？
What?!
（ナルト）うっ
（サクラ）うわっ
（ナルト）火遁 土遁 水遁を
連続で使うなんて
Using Fire Style, Earth Style
and Water Style consecutively.
普通 ありえねえってばよ
Ordinarily that's totally impossible.
He isn't called the "Copy Ninja"
for nothing...
（サクラ）コピー忍者の名は
だてじゃないわね
今になってみると
そのすごさがよく分かるわ
Now I understand how amazing he is.
Yeah...
ああ
（自来也じらいや）長期戦になりそうだのォ
This is going to be
a long-drawn-out affair.
（綱手つなで）だが 夜明けまでには
まだ だいぶある
But there's still plenty of time
until dawn.
Yes, there is.
（シズネ）はい
Things might just be settled...
案外 あっけなく
決着がつくかもしれんぞ
more quickly than you'd expect...
フフッ
ああっ
Gaara...
我愛羅
そろそろだな うん
It's almost time...
The real show's about to begin.
これからが本番だな うん
フフフッ
There!
そらよ！
He uses strange explosives...
And he's able to guide them, huh?
（我愛羅）妙な爆発物を使う
それも誘導タイプか
I've pretty much got it now.
だいたい分かった うん
（サクラ）分かっていたけど
写輪眼って とんでもない代物ね
I always knew, but...
The Sharingan is really
something else, isn't it?
ああ
Yeah...
But even more than that,
the speed of his seal formation...
でも それ以上に
先生の印を結ぶスピード
It's so fast it's tough for us
to even get near him...
速すぎて近づくのも難しい
（カカシ）はあ～
火遁 豪火球の術
Fire Style! Fireball Jutsu!
水遁 水龍弾の術
Water Style! Water Dragon Jutsu!
とりあえず
あの両手をどうにかしないと
For the time being,
we won't have a prayer
of getting the bells
鈴どころじゃないわね
unless we can do something
about both his hands.
ああ 全く
Yeah. That Kakashi-sensei's
incredibly strong for sure.
カカシ先生ってば やっぱ
むちゃくちゃ強えってばよ
シカマル以上の頭
He's smarter than Shikamaru.
He has a better sense of
smell than Kiba.
キバ以上の嗅覚
サスケ以上の写輪眼しゃりんがん
His Sharingan is better
than Sasuke's.
ゲジマユ以上の体術たいじゅつ
His Taijutsu is better
than Bushy Brow's.
経験も 俺たちよか
ず～っと豊富だし
And he's got way more...
experience than us...
（サクラ）でも カカシ先生にだって
弱点はあるはずよ
But even Kakashi-sensei must
have a weakness!
よ～く考えれば
If we think hard about it...
（ナルト）はあ～ 弱点か
Hmm. A weakness, huh...?
あ～ あった
Oh! He does...
have a weakness?!
弱点…
えっ？
What?!
（カカシ）ここまで写輪眼を
使わされるとはね
I never thought they'd make me
use my Sharingan this much...
でも まあ
日の出まではもつか
But, oh well...
I should be able to hang on
until sunrise...
手裏剣しゅりけん クナイ まだあるな
I've still got... Shuriken...
and Kunai Knives.
お～っと いかんいかん
Whoops! Mustn't do that.
昔と違って
This isn't like the old days.
本を読みながら戦えるほど
楽な相手じゃない
They're too good for me to be
able to fight them while reading.
けど 気になるなあ
But I want to know what happens.
It seems the main character
in "Make-Out Tactics"
イチャイチャタクティクスの主人公は
has some sort of incredible secret...
何か とんでもない秘密が
ありそうなんだ
早く続きが読みたい
I can't wait to read what's next...
（サクラ）ほんとに ほんとに
カカシ先生の弱点が分かったの？
R-Really?
Did you really figure out
Kakashi-sensei's weakness?
（ナルト）グフッ グフフフ…
サクラちゃん
You should be able to figure it out
カカシ先生の今までを
思い返せば分かるってばよ
if you look back on
his actions up until now.
もったいつけなくていいから
Quit stalling already...
What's his weakness, Naruto?
弱点って何よ ナルト
（ナルト）グフフフ…
それってばね
Well, you see...
（サクラ）うん うん
I get it!
（サクラ）なるほど
I never thought he'd have
a weakness like that.
まさか そんな弱点があるなんて
なっ 今までの行動を
思い返せば分かるだろ？
See?! It's clear if you think back
on his actions up until now, right?
うん うん それなら
両手を塞げるうえに
Right, right.
In addition to occupying
both his hands,
we might be able to seal off
his Sharingan if things go well.
うまくいけば写輪眼も防げるかも
そして その隙を突けば！
And then if we seize the opportunity...
ナルト やっぱあんた
意外性ナンバーワン忍者ね
Naruto...
Sure enough, you're the number one
most unpredictable Ninja!
ニヒッ
（カカシ）しかし
ヤツらの成長がうれしすぎて
Still, I was so pleased with
how much they've grown
つい はしゃぎすぎたな
that I ended up getting
kind of carried away...
今度は しばらく
ヤツらがどう出るか様子を見るか
I guess this time I'll wait and see
what kind of move they'll make.
そうと決まれば 先手必勝
Now that that's settled,
the first strike will decide this!
We'll make the first move!
こっちから仕掛けるってばよ
Right! Let's go!
そうね いきましょう
All right.
よ～し
They're fast, this time.
今度のは速いぜ うん
（我愛羅）ふんっ！
喝かつ！
（爆発音）
（カンタロウ）我愛羅！
Gaara!
They're here.
（カカシ）来たな
You're underestimating me.
なめられたもんだ
まっすぐ正面から
突っ込んでくるなんて
To think you'd attack me
head-on like that.
Now, Naruto!
今よ ナルト！
Here we go, Kakashi-sensei!
いくぞ カカシ先生！
（カカシ）えっ
At the end of Make-Out Tactics...!
イチャイチャタクティクスの
最後のオチは
Eh?! Wh-What?!
（カカシ）うっ
な… なに～！
As it happens, the main character...!
実は 主人公が…
（カカシ）ネタバラシ
He's giving away the ending!
N-No!
うわっ 危ない！
（カカシ）うう…
（カカシ）しまった
Oh, no! I still understand
what he's saying.
写輪眼のせいで
口の動きだけで言葉が分かっちまう！
I can read his lips with my Sharingan.
（カカシ）はっ…
（カカシ）ええっ…
（ナルト）ヘヘッ
（サクラ）フフッ
（カカシ）あ～！
Oh!
ハハッ 忍者は
裏の裏を読むべしって
A Ninja is supposed to read
below what's underneath.
ねっ 先生
Right, Sensei?!
（カカシ）フッ…
You got me...
（カカシ）やられたぜ
It's just like an eggshell
protecting what's inside.
（デイダラ）まるで 中身を守る卵の殻だな
しかし あれをガードしきるとは
すごいな うん
But it's incredible that he was able
to block the explosion completely.
Sand Prison!
（我愛羅）砂瀑牢さばくろう
When I look up at the sky.
sora wo miagereba
♪～
The stars, see, are sparkling.
hoshitachi ga hora matataiteru
Each giving off its own light.
kono hoshi no hitotachi mitai ni
Like the people on this planet.
samazama na hikari wo hanatte
Yeah, so among them, I too,
sono naka de boku mo
want to shine particularly bright.
hitokiwa kagayaite itain da
I close my eyes and make a vow in my heart,
me wo tojite kokoro ni chikau
and entrust my dreams to that shooting star.
nagareboshi ni yume wo takushite
I'm in my usual park.
koko wa itsumo no kouen
I can see the night scenery on the slide.
yakei ga mieru suberidai no ue
That's been my special seat for years.
mukashi kara boku no tokutouseki
Whenever I'm worried about something, I come here.
nayami ga areba koko ni kurun desu
Just like then, I'm on my way to my dreams.
ano koro no mama yume no tochuu de
But unable to fulfil them.
ima de kanaerarezu ni irun desu
Maybe this is the end of the line.
moshikashite koko ga mou shuuten
There are days when I say weak things like that.
nante yowane wo haite shimaisou na hi mo aru
But every time, I remember.
demo sono tabi ni omoidasu
That starry sky where I looked for a shooting star.
nagareboshi wo sagashite ano hoshizora
The wish I made when I was little hasn't changed even now.
chiisana koro no negaigoto ima mukashi mo kawaranai mama
When I look up at the sky.
sora wo miagereba
The stars, see, are sparkling.
hoshitachi ga hora matataiteru
Each giving off its own light.
kono hoshi no hitotachi mitai ni
Like the people on this planet.
samazama na hikari wo hanatte
Yeah, so among them, I too,
sono naka de boku mo
want to shine particularly bright.
hitokiwa kagayaite itain da
I close my eyes and make a vow in my heart,
me wo tojite kokoro ni chikau
～♪
and entrust my dreams to that shooting star.
nagareboshi ni yume wo takushite
Next Episode
オチをバラすと見せかけて
カカシをはめるとは
Who'd have thought you'd
ensnare Kakashi
by pretending to give away
the ending.
なかなかの作戦じゃないか
That's a pretty good strategy.
まあな
- You could say that.
- But if I remember correctly,
でも 自来也様の本って
確か成人向けですよねえ
Jiraiya-sama's book is
targeted for adults, right?
So when did you become an adult?
お前 いつ成人したんだ？
いや こんなの読んだうちに
入らねえって
That doesn't count as reading.
つまんなかったし
10ページくらいで すぐやめたし
It was so boring
I quit after just ten pages...
10ページ読んだそうです
It seems he read ten pages.
よ～し 有罪！
- Okay, you're guilty!
- Huh?!
ええっ？
ナルト 条令違反により
Naruto, for violating the regulations,
お前には ３日間
アカデミーの便所掃除を言い渡す
you are sentenced to clean
the Academy bathrooms for three days!
そんな～
No way!
次回「風影として」
The Kazekage Stands Tall!
Next episode: "The Kazekage Stands Tall"
NINJA ACADEMY
SPECIAL CLASS
Hello, everyone.
（カカシ）やあ 諸君
Today, we'll be discussing “Gaara”.
GAARA
今回は 我愛羅について解説するぞ
He is called “Gaara of the Desert”.
砂を変幻自在に操ることから
because he can control sand
containing Chakra.
付いたあだ名は砂漠の我愛羅
GAARA OF THE DESERT
He's the youngest of three Sand siblings.
砂の３兄弟の末っ子だ
Gaara was born with the Shukaku,
the Sand Spirit, residing within his body,
体内に 砂の化身
守鶴しゅかくを宿し
SHUKAKU
Gaara went through
the painful experience
その力を恐れた実の父親から
of his father attempting to kill him
out of fear of that power.
命を奪われかけるという
悲しい経験を持つ
Ever since that incident, he has
turned into a berserker
以来 自分のためだけに戦う
修羅と化した
who fights only for himself...
Naruto, who has been burdened with
a similar fate,
そんな我愛羅を
孤独から救ったのは
rescues Gaara from his solitude.
ナルトだった
Gaara sees Naruto fight for his friends
仲間のために戦うナルトの姿を見て
and learns what true strength
and love are really about.
我愛羅は 本当の強さとは何か
愛情とは何かを知る
After the attempted destruction of the Leaf,
木ノ葉崩し以降は
同盟国として木ノ葉の危機に加勢
the Sand assists the Leaf
in crisis as an allied land.
Gaara now leads the Village Hidden
in Sand as the Kazekage...
現在は 砂隠れの里を統率する
風影に就任
Now then, here's a question for you.
じゃあ ここで問題だ
Do you know what the character
on Gaara's forehead means?
我愛羅の額に
書かれている文字は
いったい
なんだったか
分かるかな？
The answer is... "Love"!
答は 愛
Now then, I guess I'll go home and
read some Make-Out Tactics.
さて 帰って
イチャイチャ
タクティクスでも
T
o
b
e
c
o
n
t
i
n
u
e
d
.
読むかな